WARNING! This Movie might be offensive to Righties, All Lefties, Retards, Terrorists, Pacifists, War-Mongers, Believers, the ACLU,
Conservatives, Republicans, Democrats, People of Color, Non-Speakers, & Ivy League Profs., Native Americans should be Okay.
An American Carol is a comedy, fantasy film directed by David Zucker.
A cynical anti-American Hollywood filmmaker sets out on a
crusade to abolish the 4th of July holiday.
He is visited by three spirits who take him on a hilarious journey in
an attempt to show him the true meaning of America.
Michael Malone, played by Kevin Farley.
General George S. Patton, played by Kelsey Grammer.
Osama Bin Nielsen / Grandpa, played by Leslie Nielsen.
Angel of Death, played by Trace Adkins.
Aziz, played by Robert Davi.
Mohammed, played by Geoffrey Arend.
An American Carol (released as Big Fat Important Movie in other territories) is a 2008 American satirical
comedy film directed by David Zucker and written by Zucker, Myrna Sokoloff and Lewis Friedman.
Using the framework of Charles Dickens' 1843 novella A Christmas Carol, the film follows liberal filmmaker Michael Malone (a
parody of Michael Moore) as he is visited by three spirits to teach him the importance of Independence Day.
The film satirizes liberalism in the United States,
with focus on Moore's documentaries.
It stars Kevin Farley as Malone, alongside an ensemble supporting cast that includes
Kelsey Grammer, Leslie Nielsen, Trace Adkins, Robert Davi, and Jon Voight.
Theatrically released on October 3, 2008, by Vivendi Entertainment, An American Carol received
negative reviews from most critics, who found the film's humor and satire to be ineffective.
It also was a failure at the box office grossing only $7
million against a $20 million budget.
The film marked the final onscreen appearance by Dennis Hopper before his death in 2010, and the last
collaboration between Zucker and Leslie Nielsen before the latters death in the same year.
The film explores themes of parody, terrorism,
documentary filmmaking, absurd, dubious.
The tone is lighthearted.